One of the most frequently asked questions in the interviews and in universities is the binary search
tree.
So we are going to concentrate on this data structure and we are going to practice in C and Java, how
to create the binary search tree and how to implement its operations.
A binary search tree is a data structure that quickly allows us to maintain is sort that the list of
number it is called a binary tree because each Node three node has a maximum of two children, also
called a search tree because it can be used to search or the presence of a number in all the log of
and time.
This is the time complexity for searching numbers and the presence of no log, and it's led then and
and and square.
So.
The properties that separate the binary search tree from regular binary is all nodes of the left sub
tree are less than that would no.
This is very important.
This is the key and the basics of binary search three BSD that all node of the left sub tree are less
than the root note.
All nodes of the rights up tree are more than the root note, so the left is then less than the root
and the right is greater than the root.
Both sap trees of each node are also BSD burner binary search tree.
They have the above two properties.
If we have left and right, some trees, also these sub trees comply comply.
The rules that the left is less than the root and the root is less than the right values.
OK, consider this to binary trees.
The binary on the right is not a binary search tree, because the rights of Tree of the Node three contains
a value is smaller than it.
OK, so if we have the the sub three three says that the two contains.
Let me show you this city is less than eight, okay, then less than greater than eight.
Yes.
City, this is the road one and six contains six.
Yes, there are six is greater than three.
Yes.
One is less than three.
Till now, it's good.
Two is less than six.
Yes.
But it is great that less than the road and it should contain all the elements of six of the route.
Six should be greater than three.
And this is why this right?
No, the road three is not binary circuitry.
Consider this example.
We have eight.
This is the top.
So if we divide this three.
Personally, I prefer making like this in order to check if there's a binary search tree or not.
I have divided this into left and right.
All the components here.
If I have one million component, one million note, they should be less than eight.
If there is any of these thoughts greater than a, then directly it is not a binary search three, one,
three, six and four.
They are less than eight.
So it's OK.
No, I divide also this into two main components.
The left and the right one is less than three.
Yes, all of these component nodes should be greater than three and less than eight.
So if there's four and six, so therefore we have left left.
Sub three is applying the binary search to the three rules.
If we look to the right, if there's greater than eight, yes, if any node on it greater than eight.
Yes, if any node on it less than eight, then this is not a binary surgery.
So therefore it applies all the rules.
This part is true and this part is true, and therefore this is a binary.